Okay. So, let's implement transfer learning encode.
Ok下面我们在代码中实现迁移学习
In this notebook, I'm going to be using
在此 notebook 中 我将使用预训练的 VGG 16 网络
a pretrained VGG 16 network whose architecture is pictured here,
它的结构如图所示
and I'll apply what it's learned to a totally new task.
我会将它的经验应用到全新的任务上
So, we know that this model is made of a series of convolutional and pooling layers,
我们知道此模型由一系列卷积层和池化层组成
and at the end it has three fully-connected layers that act as a final classifier.
最后有三个全连接层 充当最终分类器
In this notebook, we'll be using a pretrained model that was trained for
在此 notebook 中 我们将使用预训练的模型 该模型训练了很长时间
a very long time to reach a high accuracy in classifying images in the ImageNet dataset.
在分类 ImageNet 数据集中的图像方面取得了很高的准确率
This dataset has a thousand image classes,
此数据集有 1000 个图像类别
and so the final output layer produces a thousand class scores.
因此最终输出层生成了 1000 个类别分数
But in this notebook, I'll show you how to change this last layer and tune
但在此 notebook 中 我将演示如何更改最后的层级
this classification portion of the model to
并微调模型的分类器部分
apply it to the task of flower classification,
以便将它应用到花朵分类任务上
and I'll show you our flower dataset in a moment.
稍后我将展示花朵数据集
It includes five different classes of flowers.
它包含 5 个不同的花朵类别
Some flowers: tulips, roses, dandelions, and daisies.
分别是太阳花 郁金香 玫瑰 蒲公英和雏菊
To customize the VGG model for this task,
要针对此任务自定义 VGG 模型
my plan will be to freeze or lock the weights in the convolutional and pooling layers.
我打算冻结或锁定卷积层和池化层中的权重
This portion of the network will act as
这部分充当固定特征提取器
a fixed feature extractor that all our training images will go through.
并使所有训练图像经过这部分
Then I'm going to replace the final layer of
然后将分类部分的最终层级
the classification portion with a new fully-connected layer,
替换为新的全连接层
one that produces 5-class scores instead of a thousand as output.
从而生成 5 个类别分数 而不是 1000 个类别分数
After placing this last layer I'm going to allow
替换最后一个层级之后
all three of these fully connected layers to train.
我将训练所有这三个全连接层
This means that I'll be fine tuning the weights in two of the linear layers,
意味着我将微调其中两个线性层级的权重
and newly train the weights in this last layer.
并以全新方式训练最后一个层级中的权重
So let's get started with this task.
我们开始吧
First I'm going to load in my usual libraries and check if a GPU device is available.
首先照常加载库并检查 GPU 设备是否可用
For now since I'm going through this exercise,
因为我是在讲解练习
I'm using my laptop CPU.
暂时我将使用笔记本 CPU
Then I'm going to load in my data as usual.
然后照常加载数据
This time my data is in training and test directories.
这次 数据位于训练和测试目录中
Each sub-directory represents one particular flower class.
每个子目录代表一种花朵类别
This structure makes it easy to load in this data using pi torches image folder class.
这种结构使我们能够使用 PyTorch 的 ImageFolder 类轻松地加载数据
This class just assumes that images are in their correctly labeled folders.
该类假定图像都位于标注正确的文件夹里
So, all sunflowers are in a sunflowers folder for example.
也就是说 所有太阳花都位于太阳花文件夹里
Now, I know that VGG expects to see 224 by 224 square images as input.
因为 VGG 要求输入图像是 224x224 方形图像
So, I'll resize all of my images using a data transform and load it in.
因此我将使用 data_transform 调整所有图像的大小并加载图像
I'll just load in training and test data for now.
暂时只加载训练和测试数据
You can choose to separate out a validation set should you want to,
你也可以划分出验证集
and you can see we only have about 3,000 training images and even fewer test images.
可以看出我们只有大约 3,000 张训练图像 测试图像更少
This is a lot smaller than say something like our MNIST dataset.
它比 MNIST 数据集小多了
So, it will be interesting to see how transfer learning works for such a small dataset.
我们也可以通过这次试验看看迁移学习对这种小规模数据集来说效果如何
In here I'm using the DataLoader class to load in data in batches.
在这里使用 DataLoader 类分批加载数据
Finally I'm going to visualize a batch of this data.
最后可视化一批数据
Here I see a variety of flowers and their respective labels,
可以看到各种花朵和相应的标签
and we can see actually the variety in these images.
并且可以看出这些图像的变化
Some flowers are very close up while others are really far away.
有些花朵是特写 而有些镜头拍得很远
So, we can tell that this task will be more challenging
相比于那些经过预处理的、花朵都刻意居中的数据集相比
than if flowers were carefully centered and preprocessed.
这个任务更有挑战性
After loading the data next comes defining the model.
加载数据后 接下来定义模型
Now, the first step in working with
使用预训练模型的第一步是
a pretrained model is knowing how to look at the structure that already exists.
知道如何查看已经存在的结构
Here I'm going to load in the VGG 16 model from pi torches model library,
在这里从 PyTorch 的 models 库中加载 VGG 16 模型
which contain the many commonly used models.
该库包含很多常用的模型
I want this model to be pretrained and I'm
我希望此模型已预训练
calling it by name and storing it in this variable.
按名称调用它并存储在此变量里
Once it's loaded in, I'll print it out to see all the layers.
加载完毕后 输出模型并看看所有层级
Here I can see the entire VGG network.
可以在这里看到完整的 VGG 网络
First, there's a sequence of layers that's called features,
首先 有一系列层级 叫做 features
a series of convolutional and max-pooling layers.
它们是一系列卷积层和池化层
Then I have another group of layers down here called the classifier,
然后在下面是另一组层级 叫做 classifier
and this is where our three fully-connected linear layers are.
它们是三个全连接线性层级
I can also see things like how many inputs and outputs each of these layers have.
还可以看到每个层级有多少输入和输出等
Now, I can refer to any of these layers,
现在我可以按名称引用任何层级
groups of layers, or individual layers by name.
无论是一组层级还是单个层级
For example, I can type vgg16.features to get this whole group of layers,
例如 我可以输入 vgg16.features 引用这整个层级群组
or to refer to this last linear layer I can refer to
或者要引用最后这个线性层级
VGG 16 classifier section and the value six.
我可以输入 vgg16.classifier[6]
For example here I can access
例如 我可以在这里
that last linear layer and print out how many in features and out features it has,
访问最后一个线性层级并输出它的输入特征数量和输出特征数量
and we can see that these values line up with what we printed out before.
可以看出这些值与之前输出的值保持一致
Now, that you know how to read in a pretrained model,
现在你已经知道如何读取预训练的模型
next I'm going to show you how to freeze the weights in the feature layers and replace
接下来我将演示如何冻结特征层级中的权重
this last layer with a new linear layer suited to our flower classification task.
并将最后一个层级替换为适合花朵分类任务的新线性层级